In this video, we're going to look at
在此视频中
deployment model and sagemaker with a lot more detail.
我们将详细了解如何在 SageMaker 中部署模型
To follow along, open up the Boston Housing XGBoost Deploy low-level notebook.
要跟着操作 请打开 Boston Housing - XGBoost (Deploy) - Low Level notebook
Again the majority of this notebook is the same as the low-level notebook that we
此 notebook 的大部分内容都与
went through that use the batch transform method for testing the resulting model.
使用批量转换方法测试模型的低阶 notebook 一样
To remind ourselves of how this works,
下面看看整个流程
first we load up any of the necessary modules.
首先加载必要的模块
Then we download and prepare the data,
然后下载并准备数据
but in this case since we're using data provided by SKLearn, it's very simple.
但是这次我们使用 sklearn 提供的数据 流程很简单
We split that up into a training validation and testing set,
我们将数据拆分成训练 验证和测试集
then we save the data locally and upload it to S3.
然后将数据保存到本地并上传到 S3
Once our training data is available on S3,
将训练数据上传到 S3 后
we can set up the training job where we
开始设置训练作业
describe all of the important bits like for example,
我们需要指定参数
what algorithm we want to use,
例如要使用什么算法
the hyperparameter specific to that algorithm and where our data is stored.
该算法特定的超参数以及数据的存储位置
Once we have described the training job,
设定好训练作业后
we then ask SageMaker to create and run
请求 SageMaker 创建并运行该训练作业
that training job and we can wait for that job to complete.
等待作业运行完毕
Once the training job terminates,
训练作业运行完毕后
the output of the machine learning algorithm in this case XG Boost,
机器学习算法（即 XGBoost）的输出将保存到 S3 中
is saved to S3 and those resulting files are called the "Model Artifacts."
这些文件称为模型工件
We can then create a model inside of
然后 我们可以在 SageMaker 中创建一个模型
SageMaker by specifying which model artifacts should be
我们将指定要使用哪些模型工件
used along with which docker container contains the appropriate inference code.
并指定包含相应推理代码的 docker 容器
Just like in the previous video,
就像在上个视频中一样
instead of testing the model using the batch- transform functionality,
我们不使用批量转换功能测试模型
we're going to deploy the model and then send the test data to the deployed endpoint.
而是部署模型 然后向部署的端点发送测试数据
Remember, in SageMaker, deploying a model means creating an endpoint and that endpoint,
在 SageMaker 中部署模型是指创建一个端点
from the user's perspective is just a URL that we can send data to.
从用户的角度来看 该端点就是一个 URL 我们可以向其发送数据
Behind the scenes, things are a little more complicated but
但是在后台要复杂一些
fortunately SageMaker takes care of most of the heavy lifting.
幸运的是 SageMaker 会帮助我们处理大部分工作
What this means for us is that to deploy a model,
所以在部署模型时
means to create an endpoint and to create an endpoint we need to tell
我们需要创建一个端点 为了创建端点
SageMaker in details about how that endpoint should operate.
我们需要详细告诉 SageMaker 该端点应该如何运行
In other words, we need to create an endpoint configuration.
也就是说 我们需要进行端点配置
Just like most of the objects that we deal with instead of SageMaker,
就像 SageMaker 中的大部分对象一样
an endpoint must have a name and that name must be unique.
端点必须有名称 并且是唯一的
So we're going to use the same trick that we've used before by
我们将采用和之前一样的技巧
appending a timestamp to the end of our chosen name.
在所选的名称后面附加时间戳
Once we have a name, we need to specify a list of what are called production variants.
设定名称后 我们需要指定一系列的生产变体
In effect these are different versions of the same model or different models.
它们是同一模型（或不同模型）的不同版本
And endpoints sort of acts like a uniform resource that we can send data to.
端点就像是一个统一资源 我们可以向其发送数据
SageMaker can then take the data that is sent to an endpoint and if we wanted to,
SageMaker 然后会获取我们发送给端点的数据
split it up among different models.
如果需要的话 SageMaker 会在不同的模型之间拆分数据
For now, we only want to deploy a single model at
暂时我们只在端点上部署一个模型
our endpoint and so our production variants consists of a single item,
所以 ProductionVariants 包含一项
and that single item is the model that we specified,
这一项就是我们
that we created earlier.
之前创建的模型
Once we ask SageMaker to create the endpoint configuration,
要求 SageMaker 创建端点配置后
a new object has been created.
它会新建一个对象
Now this endpoint configuration can be thought of as
这个端点配置可以看做一个蓝图
a blueprint that we can use as many times as
我们日后可以多次使用该蓝图
we need to in the future and it tells SageMaker how to create a specific endpoint.
它会告诉 SageMaker 如何创建特定的端点
So for example, if I go back to the SageMaker console,
例如 回到 SageMaker 控制台
and on the left-hand side here I look at endpoint configurations,
在左侧点击“Endpoint configurations”
you can see this first one here is the endpoint configuration that we just created.
第一个是我们刚刚创建的端点配置
So this will stay here and perpetuity and we can create an endpoint using this blueprint,
它会永远保留在这里 我们可以随时使用
this configuration whenever we'd like to.
该蓝图创建一个端点
Heading back to the notebook,
回到 notebook
we can now ask SageMaker to create an endpoint based on the configuration we just made.
我们现在可以要求 SageMaker 根据我们刚刚设定的配置创建一个端点
Again just like always,
和之前一样
we have to make sure to specify a name and that name must be unique.
我们需要指定一个唯一名称
So now SageMaker is setting up our endpoint in the background and as before,
现在 SageMaker 正在后台设置端点
we can use this method here to see
像之前一样 我们可以使用此方法
a visual output as to how our endpoint construction is progressing.
直观地查看端点的配置进度
While SageMaker works on setting up our end point,
在 SageMaker 设置端点期间
let's take a look and see what was created.
我们来看看创建了什么
If we head back to the SageMaker console,
切换到 SageMaker 控制台
remember that this object here is the endpoint configuration that we made,
这个对象是我们刚刚创建的端点配置
and if we further click on the endpoints listing here on the left,
点击左侧的“Endpoints”
we can see the endpoint that we just asked SageMaker to
可以看到我们刚刚要求 SageMaker 创建的端点
create and currently it is in the process of being created.
目前它正在创建中
So we'll wait for SageMaker to finish making this endpoint for us.
下面等待 SageMaker 为我们创建好端点
Now we can see that our endpoint is in-service.
现在看到端点处于 InService 状态了
If we head back to the notebook,
切换到 notebook
we can see that the process of creating our endpoint has been completed as well.
可以看到端点创建流程也结束了
So now we can test the model,
下面可以测试模型了
which as we said before means we can serialize our data and then send it to an end point.
正如之前提到的 我们需要序列化数据并发送给端点
Now in this case,
但是现在
because we don't have a predictor object,
我们没有 predictor 对象了
we need to serialize the data ourselves which is pretty straightforward.
需要手动序列化数据 过程很简单
We basically just turn our matrix which is a listing
我们将矩阵（记录列表）
of records into a comma delimited file, so we do that.
转化成按逗号分隔的文件
Then we use the SageMaker runtime client to call our endpoint with
然后使用 sagemaker_runtime_client 调用该端点
the specified name with content which is
指定名称和 csv 格式的数据
a CSV file and then we include the data we wish to have our model process.
然后包含希望模型处理的数据
The resulting object is then
生成的对象是序列化输出
a serialized output which we need to convert to
我们需要转换为字符串
a string and then turn back into a numpy array.
然后再转换回 numpy 数组
Once we have our resulting output,
获得输出后
we can then plot a nice little graph.
我们可以绘制图形 看看运行效果
As before, once we're done using our endpoint we need to shut it down.
与之前一样 使用完端点后 关闭端点
But I'm going to show you a slightly different way to shut down
但是我将介绍一个
the endpoint from just using the notebook methods.
与使用 notebook 方法不一样的关闭方式
So if we go back to the SageMaker console,
切换到 SageMaker 控制台
and look at our endpoint.
看看我们的端点
Clicking on this endpoint here gives us some more information about it.
点击此端点可以查看更多信息
In particular, right here is
这是实际 URL
the actual URL that can be used to send data to our endpoint.
我们可以使用该 URL 向端点发送数据
Now it turns out, not just anyone can send data
并非任何人都能向其发送数据
here and we'll talk about that more in detail later on.
稍后我会详细讲解的
Another useful feature of this page is this 'Delete' button.
这个页面还有一个实用功能 叫做“Delete”按钮
If I click on the delete button,
点击“Delete”后
it will shut down the endpoint for us.
将关闭端点
So we don't have to use the notebook to shut down the end points.
所以我们不需要使用 notebook 关闭端点
We can use this SageMaker console as well.
也可以使用这个 SageMaker 控制台按钮
And yes we'd like to delete it
是的 我们想要删除端点